Daniel Parkson Tano

237674128573 • tanoparksonsilencer@gmail.com • <u>linkedin.com/in/daniel-parkson-tano/</u>
• https://twitter.com/ParksonDaniel • <u>https://www.parksontano.com/</u>

Full Stack Developer

I am an experienced Full Stack Web and Mobile Developer specializing in Django and React. I excel in full-stack mobile and web development, ensuring efficient performance through responsive designs and streamlined code. My attention to detail, problem-solving skills, and commitment to quality guarantee timely delivery and excellent results.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Upscale innovation • Romote (Mumbai, India) • Full-time • 12/2022 - Present **Lead Full Stack developer**

- Developed, tested, and deployed a web-based application for a company's HR management in 1 month, increasing user HR performance by 90%.
- Reduced web development time by 15.3% in 3 months, resulting in 14.87% annual cost savings.
- Created and implemented an efficient project management system that improved team productivity by 30%, resulting in quicker project delivery times and increased client satisfaction.
- Led a team of developers to successfully design and implement a complex web application using Git for version control and AWS for hosting.

Tantorial • Yaounde • 07/2021 - Present

Full-stack Developer

- Led a team of developers to successfully design and implement a complex web application using Git for version control and AWS for hosting.
- Developed efficient and scalable full-stack solutions for various projects, resulting in high levels of satisfaction and increased repeat business.
- Implemented agile methodologies and best practices, resulting in a 30% increase in efficiency and productivity.
- Developed custom solutions and integrations, resulting in a 25% reduction in overhead costs while improving overall user experience.

Imobbis • Yaounde • Part-time • 06/2021 - 05/2022

Django Back End Developer

- Developed and maintained a real estate-oriented social network in Cameroon using Django and Django Rest Framework.
- Implemented Git version control system to facilitate efficient teamwork with colleagues.
- Contributed to the development of key features such as user authentication, property listing, and messaging functionality.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science (BSc) in Mathematics and Computer Science

higher teacher training college, university of maroua • 10/2016 - 08/2019

Google Data Analytics Certificate

Google Frontend Developer Certification

Coursera • 01/2023 - 04/2023

SKILLS

Software Development, Django REST Framework, React.js, Programming Languages, Pandas (Software), Python (Programming Language), JavaScript, RESTful WebServices, JS Frameworks